<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modeling on ASML-YONSEI</title>
    <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/tags/modeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modeling on ASML-YONSEI</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/tags/modeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SST memory timescale</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/Climate/tau_SST/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/Climate/tau_SST/</guid>
      <description> Question Key points Question Key points </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/Modeling/MITgcm/atmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/Modeling/MITgcm/atmos/</guid>
      <description>MITgcm includes an atmospheric physics as a package and it is in aim_v23. The following is the description of this package you can find in MITgcm/pkg/aim_v23.&#xA;aim_v23_description.tex Package aim_v23 contains code for an intermediate complexity atmospheric physics scheme derived from the physics in the SPEEDY model of Franco Molteni. The package contains the SPEEDY physics routines, re-cast to work with pressure coordinate dynamics, together with code that interfaces the SPEEDY internal arrays to the MITgcm dynamical kernel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current-wind interaction in the Kuroshio extension</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/airsea/current_ajin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/airsea/current_ajin/</guid>
      <description>Relative wind (RW; wind relative to surface currents) has been shown to play a crucial role in air-sea interactions, influencing both atmospheric and oceanic dynamics. While the RW effects through momentum flux are well-documented, those through turbulent heat fluxes remain unknown. In this study, we investigate two distinct surface current feedbacks – those associated with the momentum flux and turbulent heat fluxes – by modifying respective bulk formulations in the regional ocean-atmosphere coupled system, and analyze both immediate and seasonal changes in the boundary layers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IOD&amp;ENSO</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/AtmosCirc/IOD_DHKIM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/AtmosCirc/IOD_DHKIM/</guid>
      <description>The variabilities in the tropical climate are accompanied by changes in tropical deep convection, which can influence the atmospheric circulation in the Southern Hemisphere (SH). We investigate the processes and results of the teleconnection between the tropics and extratropics in the Southern Hemisphere.&#xA;Key points methodology Results Application Publication Key points Indian Ocean Dipole (IOD)’s Rossby wave train is partially similar to the climatology; a negative IOD enormously increases zonal wavenumber 3 IOD (El Niño Southern Oscillation, or ENSO) is negatively (positively) correlated with zonal wavenumber 2 and 3 (1) in austral spring The extremely positive IOD in 2019 exhibited more significant increases and unusual changes in wave patterns methodology The research period is SON (September-November) when the response of the Southern Hemisphere atmosphere to the IOD and ENSO is significant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meridional Wind on the Southern Ocean</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/OceanCirc/channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/OceanCirc/channel/</guid>
      <description>Antarctica experiences strong katabatic winds, which are powerful enough to drive sea ice away from the coastline. However, there remains significant uncertainty regarding the strength of these winds and their influence on Southern Ocean circulation. In this study, we investigate the responses of Antarctic sea ice and ocean circulation to southerly wind perturbations.&#xA;Key points Numerical simulation Configuration Perturbations on the meridional wind Results Application Publication Key points The southerly wind anomaly over the Antarctic seasonal ice zone enhances the seasonality of sea ice extent and volume.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top-down and Bottom-up Mixing within the Ocean Mixed Layer</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/Biogeochem/autumnbloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/Biogeochem/autumnbloom/</guid>
      <description>In the ocean, phytoplankton can grow in the euphotic zone, resulting in high concentrations near the sea surface. During the autumn, the ocean&amp;rsquo;s upper layer lacks nutrients, as most of the nutrients supplied by winter mixing are depleted because already used in the summer, leaving nutrients concentrated in the lower layers. Without vertical motion, phytoplankton near the sea surface are hard to grow in such conditions. However, as the stratification weakens and the mixed layer depth (MLD) begins to deepen in the autumn, nutrients can be entrained into the MLD and supplied to the upper layers, potentially triggering an autumn phytoplankton bloom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ocean</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/Modeling/MITgcm/ocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/Modeling/MITgcm/ocean/</guid>
      <description>There is a verification called global_ocean.cs32x15 that uses the same grid as aim.5l_cs. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get used to it before trying the atmosphere-ocean coupled model.&#xA;description of this experiment compile preparation model integration analysis additional experiments adding age tracer simulation with sea-ice package description of this experiment The description of this example is provided in the README file. global_ocean.cs32x15 global ocean using the cubed-sphere grid 32x32x32 with 15 levels&#xA;=================================================================</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>coupled</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/Modeling/MITgcm/coupled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/Modeling/MITgcm/coupled/</guid>
      <description>MITgcm can be an atmosphere-ocean coupled model using its own coupler. There is a verification called cpl_aim+ocn, and it is a coupled version of atmospheric and oceanic model on cubed sphere grid that we did so far. The instruction below can be found in README file in cpl_aim+ocn to run the coupled simulation.&#xA;README.md Atmosphere-Ocean coupled set-up example &amp;ldquo;cpl_aim+ocn&amp;rdquo; using simplified atmospheric physics (AIM), in realistic configuration (orography &amp;amp; continent) with land and seaice component, on cubed-sphere (cs-32) grid.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
