<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research in ASML on ASML-YONSEI</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research in ASML on ASML-YONSEI</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Air-sea Interaction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/airseacouple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 07:49:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/airseacouple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;flex align-center gdoc-page__anchorwrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3 id=&#34;air-sea-interactions&#34;&#xA;    &gt;&#xA;        Air-sea interactions&#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a data-clipboard-text=&#34;http://localhost:1313/research/airseacouple/#air-sea-interactions&#34; class=&#34;gdoc-page__anchor clip flex align-center&#34; title=&#34;Anchor to: Air-sea interactions&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor to: Air-sea interactions&#34; href=&#34;#air-sea-interactions&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;gdoc-icon gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&#34;#gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are investigating air-sea couplings to understand the climate system in both large- and meso-scale processes. For the research, we are using a coupled atmosphere-ocean model with biogeochemical module and explore the physical processes and their impact on biogeochemical processes including the carbon cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;flex align-center gdoc-page__anchorwrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3 id=&#34;air-sea-cosub2sub-exchange&#34;&#xA;    &gt;&#xA;        Air-sea CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; exchange&#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a data-clipboard-text=&#34;http://localhost:1313/research/airseacouple/#air-sea-cosub2sub-exchange&#34; class=&#34;gdoc-page__anchor clip flex align-center&#34; title=&#34;Anchor to: Air-sea CO2 exchange&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor to: Air-sea CO2 exchange&#34; href=&#34;#air-sea-cosub2sub-exchange&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;gdoc-icon gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&#34;#gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While investigating the role of mesoscale eddies using both observations and numerical models, we find quite complicated, yet very interesting impacts of eddies in the Southern Ocean. The air-sea CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; exchange depends on the difference in partial pressure of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) between air and ocean. Since atmospheric pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; is nearly uniform and well-known, oceanic pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; is a key factor for the air-sea CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; exchange. In contrast to CFC-11, not only physical but also biogeochemical states of the ocean influence pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, which requires more comprehensive analysis. In summer, oceanic pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; is lower in anticyclones while cyclonic eddies have higher oceanic pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Interestingly, this relationship is flipped in winter and anticyclones/cyclones have higher/lower pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. The seasonality of the relationship between eddies and pCO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; is resulted from the time-varying balance between two opposing thermal and DIC effects. Please refer to our paper, &lt;a&#xA;  class=&#34;gdoc-markdown__link&#34;&#xA;  href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/2016JC011714/full&#34;&#xA;&gt;&lt;U&gt;Song et al. (2016)&lt;/U&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Circulation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/southernocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 07:49:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/southernocean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex align-center gdoc-page__anchorwrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3 id=&#34;southern-ocean&#34;&#xA;    &gt;&#xA;        Southern Ocean&#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a data-clipboard-text=&#34;http://localhost:1313/research/southernocean/#southern-ocean&#34; class=&#34;gdoc-page__anchor clip flex align-center&#34; title=&#34;Anchor to: Southern Ocean&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor to: Southern Ocean&#34; href=&#34;#southern-ocean&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;gdoc-icon gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&#34;#gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Southern Ocean is unique. Consistent eastward wind results in upwelling of the water from the interior of the ocean, providing a passage for the exchange between the atmosphere and deep ocean.&#xA;Unlike other major ocean basins, it does not have boundaries so that water circulates all around Antarctica. This wind-driven current is called Antarctic Circumpolar Current (ACC) and flows eastward connecting Atlantic, Pacific and Indian Oceans. The Southern Ocean plays an important role in earth&amp;rsquo;s climate. It stores up to 40% of anthropogenic carbon dioxide (CO2) that enters the ocean. The connection between the atmosphere and subsurface ocean makes the Southern Ocean the area where the ocean breathes. The Southern Ocean is also biologically interesting area. The biological activity has a strong seasonal variability (Fig. 1) and is generally limited by light in winter and micronutrient in summer. Although intensive biological activities in the SO (Fig. 1) promote carbon dioxide (CO2) uptake, the overturning circulation and the intensive vertical mixing in winter allow CO2 in the deep ocean to escape to the atmosphere at the same time.&#xA;The Southern Ocean has high eddy activities. When the upwelling brings dense water to the surface, it makes the ocean high in potential energy and eddies convert it to kinetic energy. My research interest lies on how these eddies modify the air-sea CO2 flux and other oceanic biogeochemical states.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State estimation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/dataassimilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 07:49:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/dataassimilation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex align-center gdoc-page__anchorwrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3 id=&#34;california-current-system&#34;&#xA;    &gt;&#xA;        California Current System&#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a data-clipboard-text=&#34;http://localhost:1313/research/dataassimilation/#california-current-system&#34; class=&#34;gdoc-page__anchor clip flex align-center&#34; title=&#34;Anchor to: California Current System&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor to: California Current System&#34; href=&#34;#california-current-system&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;gdoc-icon gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&#34;#gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The California Current System is located at the east of the north Pacific. Equatorward upwelling favorable wind draws nutrient-rich water from the interior to the surface making ocean very productive. In fact, approximately 35% of wild-caught fish come from here (Kudela et al., 2009). I investigated the interaction between wind, upwelling and marine ecosystem using ocean circulation model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
