<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MITgcm on ASML-YONSEI</title>
    <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MITgcm on ASML-YONSEI</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/install/</guid>
      <description>Here are a couple of things that we need to do prior to the model experiments.&#xA;Installing MITgcm Testing MITgcm configuring the system compile run python miniconda python package JupyterLab Installing MITgcm MITgcm documentation Testing MITgcm MITgcm includes a set of examples that can be run straight out of the box. For example, you can try to follow the documentation on barotropic gyre and see you can run the model without an issue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/atmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/atmos/</guid>
      <description>MITgcm includes an atmospheric physics as a package and it is in aim_v23. The following is the description of this package you can find in MITgcm/pkg/aim_v23.&#xA;aim_v23_description.tex Package aim_v23 contains code for an intermediate complexity atmospheric physics scheme derived from the physics in the SPEEDY model of Franco Molteni. The package contains the SPEEDY physics routines, re-cast to work with pressure coordinate dynamics, together with code that interfaces the SPEEDY internal arrays to the MITgcm dynamical kernel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ocean</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/ocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/ocean/</guid>
      <description>There is a verification called global_ocean.cs32x15 that uses the same grid as aim.5l_cs. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get used to it before trying the atmosphere-ocean coupled model.&#xA;description of this experiment compile preparation model integration analysis additional experiments adding age tracer simulation with sea-ice package description of this experiment The description of this example is provided in the README file. global_ocean.cs32x15 global ocean using the cubed-sphere grid 32x32x32 with 15 levels&#xA;=================================================================</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>coupled</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/coupled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/MITgcm/coupled/</guid>
      <description>MITgcm can be an atmosphere-ocean coupled model using its own coupler. There is a verification called cpl_aim+ocn, and it is a coupled version of atmospheric and oceanic model on cubed sphere grid that we did so far. The instruction below can be found in README file in cpl_aim+ocn to run the coupled simulation.&#xA;README.md Atmosphere-Ocean coupled set-up example &amp;ldquo;cpl_aim+ocn&amp;rdquo; using simplified atmospheric physics (AIM), in realistic configuration (orography &amp;amp; continent) with land and seaice component, on cubed-sphere (cs-32) grid.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
