<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Southern Ocean on ASML-YONSEI</title>
    <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/tags/southern-ocean/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Southern Ocean on ASML-YONSEI</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 23:32:04 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/tags/southern-ocean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ocean Circulation</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/southernocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 07:49:59 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/southernocean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex align-center gdoc-page__anchorwrap&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h3 id=&#34;southern-ocean&#34;&#xA;    &gt;&#xA;        Southern Ocean&#xA;    &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a data-clipboard-text=&#34;https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/southernocean/#southern-ocean&#34; class=&#34;gdoc-page__anchor clip flex align-center&#34; title=&#34;Anchor to: Southern Ocean&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor to: Southern Ocean&#34; href=&#34;#southern-ocean&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;gdoc-icon gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;use xlink:href=&#34;#gdoc_link&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Southern Ocean is unique. Consistent eastward wind results in upwelling of the water from the interior of the ocean, providing a passage for the exchange between the atmosphere and deep ocean.&#xA;Unlike other major ocean basins, it does not have boundaries so that water circulates all around Antarctica. This wind-driven current is called Antarctic Circumpolar Current (ACC) and flows eastward connecting Atlantic, Pacific and Indian Oceans. The Southern Ocean plays an important role in earth&amp;rsquo;s climate. It stores up to 40% of anthropogenic carbon dioxide (CO2) that enters the ocean. The connection between the atmosphere and subsurface ocean makes the Southern Ocean the area where the ocean breathes. The Southern Ocean is also biologically interesting area. The biological activity has a strong seasonal variability (Fig. 1) and is generally limited by light in winter and micronutrient in summer. Although intensive biological activities in the SO (Fig. 1) promote carbon dioxide (CO2) uptake, the overturning circulation and the intensive vertical mixing in winter allow CO2 in the deep ocean to escape to the atmosphere at the same time.&#xA;The Southern Ocean has high eddy activities. When the upwelling brings dense water to the surface, it makes the ocean high in potential energy and eddies convert it to kinetic energy. My research interest lies on how these eddies modify the air-sea CO2 flux and other oceanic biogeochemical states.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
