<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Southern Ocean on ASML-YONSEI</title>
    <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/tags/southern-ocean/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Southern Ocean on ASML-YONSEI</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/tags/southern-ocean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ocean</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/OceanCirc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/OceanCirc/</guid>
      <description>We are investigating the general ocean circulation in varied scales.&#xA;Southern Ocean Meridional Wind on the Antarctic sea ice Patagonian shelf California Current System Upwelling source waters Southern Ocean The Southern Ocean is unique. Consistent eastward wind results in upwelling of the water from the interior of the ocean, providing a passage for the exchange between the atmosphere and deep ocean. Unlike other major ocean basins, it does not have boundaries so that water circulates all around Antarctica.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air-Sea Interaction</title>
      <link>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/airsea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://airsea.yonsei.ac.kr/research/airsea/</guid>
      <description>We are investigating air-sea couplings to understand the climate system in both large- and meso-scale processes. For the research, we are using a coupled atmosphere-ocean model with biogeochemical module and explore the physical processes and their impact on biogeochemical processes including the carbon cycle.&#xA;Air-Sea coupled simulation Current-wind interaction in the Kuroshio Extension Air-sea coupling frequencies in the coupled model Dumping of heat by tropical cyclones Air-Sea CO2 exchange Air-Sea CFC-11 exchange Air-Sea coupled simulation Current-wind interaction in the Kuroshio Extension Surface flow can modulate the air-sea momentum and turbulent heat flux.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
